### MATHIAS SOEHOLM

#### SOFTWARE ENGINEER



A passionate Software Engineer with an eye for the details and a drive to deliver high quality products. Will walk the extra mile to test and clean up work, rather than rush to close an issue.

Experience with working on large-scale projects, where good architecture is key to success.

Used to implementing highly polished user interfaces with animations and plenty of juicyness.

#### EXPERIENCE

may. 2019 - present

Trifork - Software Pilot

- Working on LEGO® Education SPIKE™ Prime, mostly with TypeScript and React but also Swift on iOS.
- Teached React and TypeScript to developers at Unik System Design in a hands-on course.
- Mentored junior developers at LEGO, which involved a React workshop.

jun. 2018 - may. 2019

Mindfox Studios - Co-founder & Software Engineer

- Shipped two original mobile games, Space Loops and Sausage Throw.
- Worked with React Native to implement Odin ICE-Pro, from design to release in just three weeks
- Was consultant at LEGO during five months.
  Worked with two teams on the apps: LEGO®
  Movie Maker and LEGO® TV for both Android and iOS.
- Other clients include Stibo, Kamstrup, AKQA, Novo Nordisk and Destination Aarhus.

nov. 2016 - jun. 2018

BitBreak - Co-Founder & Software Engineer

- Released a VR game for HTC Vive (In Your Face TD) with 98% positive reviews on Steam (77 positive, 1 negative).
- Created an online cryptocurrency vendor with React and Redux.
- Did Unity consulting for the game Pool Legends and publisher Spil Games.
- All of this was while studying Computer Science at Aarhus University.

apr. 2013 - jun. 2016

Kiloo - Software Engineer

- Worked on a large production (Stormblades) as one of only two programmers. Implemented the entire UI and all meta features, including leaderboards and cloud synchronization.
- Made tools in Unity which are now used in one of the most downloaded mobile games ever, Subway Surfers.

aug. 2012 - apr. 2013

Campus Djursland - Workshop Instructor

 Teached game development in C# and Unity, with classes of up to 60 students.

mar. 2011 - apr. 2013 ClearCut Games - Co-Founder & Programmer

# **DETAILS**

- hiremathias.com
- github.com/mathiassoeholm
- (+45) 42 65 71 14
- Vejle, Denmark

### SKILLS

Programming Languages



Libraries and Frameworks



Tools and Software



# **EDUCATION**

Computer Science - Bachelor's degree Aarhus University 2015-2018

## INTERESTS

Strumming chords on a guitar Smashing colleauges in table tennis Trying to lift stuff at CrossFit Programming of course!